

CONTACT

- lucas.scheinkerman @gmail.com
- C LucasJSch
- in lucas-scheinkerman
- Buenos Aires, Argentina

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Native

Hebrew

Bilingual proficiency

English

Full professional proficiency

TECH SKILLS

C++	4+ yrs
Python	4+ yrs
Android	2+ yrs
Java	2+ yrs
Docker	2 yrs
Unreal Engine	1+ yrs

LUCAS SCHEINKERMAN

Software Engineer

ABOUT ME

29 years old Software Engineer located in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Looking for awesome technical challenges, eager to learn new things and do meaningful work that impacts positively in our world.

I love to learn new stuff, understand how complex systems work, and transform theoretical ideas into real things. Translated into my work, I love all aspects of complex systems design and implementation. From coding low-level C routines, to solving high-level problems using the most suitable data structures and algorithms, I find exciting each and everyone of the layers.

EDUCATION

Electronics Engineering DegreeUniversity of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires (Argentina)

2015 - 2024

WORK EXPERIENCE

Robotics simulation Engineer Unreal Empowerment, Buenos Aires (Argentina) June 2023 - Present

· Software Eng. consultant for US-Based company.

I develop simulation tools to generate artificial datasets for training Al-based aircraft navigation algorithms, ensuring compliance with specific requirements.

I use **C++** for core development and **Unreal Engine** for high-fidelity visual rendering, enhancing the realism of simulations. Also I employ **Python** for implementing **ROS** nodes and handling API client calls, effectively integrating various technologies to produce robust and accurate training environments.

Software Engineer Ekumen, Buenos Aires (Argentina) Sep 2019 - May 2022

- Software Engineering consultant for Google, where I:
 - Designed and implemented data collection and ingestion pipelines using Python's Apache Beam SDK, optimizing data processing workflows.
 - Developed Android applications focused on sensor data collection, augmented reality (AR) features, and live data plotting using Android Java SDK and C++.
 - Conducted code integration, testing, maintenance, and review to ensure high-quality software.
- Mentored new hires in introductory-level C++ training, enhancing their foundational programming skills.
- Conducted technical interviews, assessing candidate qualifications and technical expertise.

TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS



PROJECTS

Implementation of CORDIC algorithm for FPGA Implemented with VHDL

2022

Implemented the CORDIC algorithm, designing two distinct architectures to compare resource utilization and efficiency. I also created comprehensive test benches to verify the accuracy and performance of each implementation. This project led to a thorough analysis of resource consumption and efficiency, ultimately enhancing algorithm performance and reliability.

Spaceship navigation animation ☐ Implemented with WebGL, GLSL and JavaScript

2021

A university project to gain in-depth familiarity with graphics pipelines. It enhanced my understanding of graphical processing and significantly improved my ability to work with complex graphics systems.

Contribution to ARCore-ROS streamer ☐ Implemented with Android's SDK

2021

Collaborated with a colleague to implement key improvements in a repository for an Android-based app utilizing Google's ARCore module. This enhancement significantly optimized the app's ability to process odometry-related information and effectively publish it as ROS messages, thereby advancing the app's functionality and performance.

Terrarium simulator ☐ with C++ within a dockerized environment

2020

Designed and implemented a terrarium simulator with different kinds of bugs that reproduce, die and interact with each other in each simulation cycle.